iss.net 2006-12-05

# ISS Privacy Policy

**ISS and the E.U. - U.S. Safe Harbor for Privacy**

The European Commission and the U.S. Department of Commerce have developed a "safe harbor" framework of data protection principles ("Safe Harbor"). This Safe Harbor is designed to provide U.S. organizations with a means to satisfy the European Union's legal requirement that adequate data protections be afforded to personally-identifiable information transferred from the European Union to the United States. ISS' Privacy Policy is consistent with the Safe Harbor principles, and ISS has certified that its transfers of data from the European Union to the United States adhere to the Safe Harbor principles.

**Other ISS Web Sites**

You can access a number of individual Web sites developed by ISS businesses through [www.iss.net](http://www.iss.net/) ("ISS Sites"). The privacy practices of ISS Web sites conform to the ISS Privacy Policy. ISS is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of Web sites linked to [www.iss.net](http://www.iss.net/) that are not developed by ISS businesses. You are encouraged to review the privacy policies of each Web site you visit.

**Notice**

As a leading global provider of security management solutions for the Internet, protecting digital assets and ensuring safe and uninterrupted online business operations, Internet Security Systems ("ISS") understands and respects your privacy concerns when you visit our Web site. In general, you may browse through our site without providing us any information about yourself. However, we may need to request Personal Information on occasion in order to provide you with specific services that you have requested. "Personal Information" is information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person that identifies that person. At the time ISS collects Personal Information from you, it will inform you of the purposes for which it collects and uses such information, how to contact ISS with any inquiries or complaints, and the types of third parties to which it discloses such information.

"Sensitive Personal Information" is personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of an individual. If ISS collects Sensitive Personal Information from you, we will provide you with an affirmative or explicit (opt in) choice if the information is to be disclosed to a third party or used for a purpose other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. ISS will treat any information you provide and identify as sensitive as Sensitive Personal Information.

ISS.net is a general audience Web site and does not knowingly collect any personal information from children. If you are applying for employment with ISS through this Web site, please refer to our Employee Data Privacy Policy to learn how ISS handles employment/employee data information in the context of employment. ISS maintains the majority of the information collected through this Web site in the United States.

**Methods of Data Collection**

Internet Security Systems collects data in the following ways: 

  * In registration screens and online forms 
  * In the process of online purchases and sales inquiries 
  * In emails sent to Internet Security Systems from users 
  * From ISS resellers and distribution partners 

**Choice**

ISS will offer you the opportunity to choose whether your Personal Information is to be (a) disclosed to a third party or (b) used for a purpose that is incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. Generally, ISS would only disclose your Personal Information to a third party that collects or uses it under ISS' instructions or on ISS' behalf.

**Security**

ISS will take reasonable precautions to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

**Data Integrity**

ISS will not process your Personal Information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by you. To the extent necessary for those purposes, ISS will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is relevant for its intended use, accurate, complete and current.

**Access**

ISS will provide you with reasonable access to your Personal Information that it holds and will undertake reasonable steps to permit you to correct, amend or delete that information demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete.

**Transfer to Third Parties**

When ISS transfers information to a third party that is acting as an agent, before doing so it will ascertain that the third party either safeguards Personal Information consistent with this Privacy Policy, is subject to the EU Directive 95/46/EC (the EU Data Protection Directive, Safe Harbor certification in the U.S by the third party, or by being subject to another European Commission adequacy finding (e.g., company is located in Canada)). Alternatively, ISS may enter into a written agreement with such third party requiring that the third party provide at least the same level of privacy protection as required by the relevant principles of this Policy. Where ISS has knowledge that an agent is using or disclosing personal information contrary to this Policy, ISS will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure.

**Enforcement**

ISS will conduct compliance audits of its relevant privacy practices to verify adherence to this policy. Any employee that ISS determines is in violation of this policy will be subject to disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment. If you have questions regarding this policy, please contact ISS at [privacy@iss.net](mailto:privacy@iss.net) or Internet Security Systems, Inc., 6303 Barfield Road, Atlanta, GA 30328, Attn: Privacy Office. If you have any questions about the practices of this Web site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact: Webmaster at the same address or at [webmaster@iss.net](mailto:webmaster@iss.net). 

**Dispute Resolution**

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of personal information should be directed to the Privacy Office at the business or email address above. ISS will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints regarding use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy. For complaints that cannot be resolved between you and ISS, ISS has agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the European data protection authorities to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Principles.

**What data we collect and how we use it**

Internet Security Systems generally collects information for the following purposes: 

  * **To engage in transactions and communications.** Name, address, email, purchase details, and credit card/payment information may be collected and stored as a necessary part of an online transaction and its attendant history. Internet Security Systems may need to share some of this information (address, etc.) with fulfillment houses, credit card clearing houses, and other similarly situated third parties as a requirement to complete a transaction. 
  * **To provide future service and support**. Contact and other information related to products and services may be collected to assist future needs and customer support for Internet Security Systems customers. This information is also used to provide product and service updates, and similar notices. If you wish not to receive these communications please send an email to [sales@iss.net](mailto:sales@iss.net) with your contact information, including the email address that you wish to have removed. 
  * **To provide customized content.** Information may be collected to help create relevant and user-friendly Web site content and navigation. This information may include a visitor's path through the site, as well as information provided through online forms. 
  * **To respond to user inquiries and requests for information.** This information includes registrations for newsletters and sales inquiries. 
  * **To provide useful marketing information.** We may use information from you to provide timely and relevant notices of product releases and service developments. 
  * **To provide additional information on corporate events or related products.** We occasionally use your information to provide you with details on events and products that may meet your needs. 
  * **To improve our online presence.** When Internet Security Systems uses tracking devices, such as IP address logging or cookies, we do so to assist a specific function on our Web site (online store, license key distribution), or to determine which areas of our Web site are being used most heavily. This information is very important in helping us make our Web site as useful as possible, both for our customers and for the broader network security community. We do not correlate specific sessions back to the individual visiting our Web site, nor do we log the specific search terms entered into any given search engine request. Internet Security Systems creates internal reports on user demographics, Web site traffic patterns and other items that help us assess the utility and performance of our Web site. 
  * **For usage tracking.** Our Web server system automatically collects limited information about you when you request pages from our server, including your IP address. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on a network to identify your computer so that data, such as the Web pages you request, can be sent to you. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to provide general administration tasks on our Web site. Your IP address is also used to keep track of your shopping cart on any Internet Security Systems-hosted online store. In addition, the hostname (or computer name) of your computer may be looked up by our server. This information is normally captured by Web servers. We use it to help us maintain and improve our online presence. We do not use it to generate marketing lists, or to resell this information to any third party. 
  * **As a result of legal requirements.** Internet Security Systems may be required to provide personally identifiable information to comply with legally mandated reporting or process requirements. 
  * **For online registration.** Internet Security Systems has provided you with the ability to register with us. We maintain the information at our corporate headquarters in the United States and allow you to update it at any time. To change this information, please click on My Profile and log in. Please email [webmaster@iss.net](mailto:webmaster@iss.net) with any questions or concerns regarding your profile. 

**How we use Cookies**  

Some of our Web servers use cookies to assist in administering our online license key distribution system and online store. This information is temporary in nature, and is not used for any other purpose. At no time do we use cookies to capture personally identifiable information about our visitors, nor do we ever make this information available to any external organization.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

Internet Security Systems is a global company, and may share your personal information with other Internet Security Systems offices around the globe. Your information may be stored and processed in the United States, or any other country in which Internet Security Systems, its subsidiaries or agents maintain normal business operations.

As part of conducting transactions, Internet Security Systems may need to share some of this information (address, etc.) with fulfillment houses, credit card clearing houses, and other similarly situated third parties that are required to complete a transaction.

**Changes to this Policy**

This Policy may be amended from time to time, consistent with the requirements of the Safe Harbor. A change notice will be posted on the ISS web page ([www.iss.net](http://www.iss.net/)) for 60 days whenever this Policy is changed in any material way.

**ISS' Employee Data Privacy Policy**

ISS maintains the privacy of the Personal Information of its current and former employees and of applicants for employment in accordance with ISS' Employee Data Privacy Policy. A change notice will be posted on the ISS web page ([www.iss.net](http://www.iss.net/)) for 60 days whenever this policy is changed in any material way.

Thank you for visiting Internet Security Systems. 

_Last updated: 12/03/2004_
